U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5059
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records
1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5059
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 142, 1961. Trans World Airlines, Inc., vs. the Air Line Pilots Association, International, 1950-1961.
3115151
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 29, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
On August 30, 1960 the Pilots Association notified TWA that it wished to make certain changes in the existing eon-tract and submitted a new agreement. On September 19, 1960 TWA forwarded its proposals to the union, and served notice that the entire contract was open for negotiation. No agreement was reached, and on December 20, 1960 the assistance of the National Mediation Board was requested. Several attempts to settle the dispute were unsuccessful and the Pilots established November 2 at midnight as the time to strike.
The President, by Executive Order 10971 on November 1, 196l created Emergency Board No. 142 to investigate the dispute. On November 22, he appointed Donald B. Straus, Morrison Handsaker and Patrick J. Fisher to the Board, Issues in dispute were wages, hours, rules, training programs and fringe benefits. The most serious issue was the implementation of the recommendations of the Presidential Commission which bad recommended that the flight engineers merge with the pilots, that the flight deck crew be reduced from four to three, and certain other airline personnel problems.
Scope and Contents
Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency Board No. 142, 1961. Trans World Airlines, Inc. vs the Air Line Pilots Association, International, 1950-1961.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5042: U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Airlines -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States -- Sources; United States Emergency Board No. 142; Air Line Pilots Association--Sources.; Trans World Airlines-- Sources.
3115151
- Transcripts. Carriers' Exhibits. Union Exhibits. Joint Exhibits. (Box 1)
  - Transcripts. 9 volumes. 1235 pages. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 1. Map of domestic and international routes of Trans World Airlines. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 2. Outline description of Trans World Airlines. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 3. Background and nature of the dispute. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 4. The jet crew complement. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 5. Company opener made in September 1960. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    September 1960.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 6. "Schematic representation commercial jet airplane cockpit" (scale drawing of Boeing 707 cockpit). (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Missing.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 7. Breakdown of major carriers using four-man cockpit crews and those using three-man cockpit crews. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 8. Report to the President of Feinsinger Commission, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    May 24, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 9. White House press release referring to the Feinsinger Commission report of May 24, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 10. Feinsinger Commission report dated October 17, 1961. Statement by the President on the airlines controversy. Press release of the Feinsinger Commission. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    October 17, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 11. Agreement between Trans World Airlines, Incorporated, ad the Air Line Pilots in the service of Trans World Airlines, Incorporated as represented by the Air Line Pilots Association, International, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    May 22, 1959
  - Carriers' Exhibit 12. Pilot Retirement - Example A. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 13. Pilot Retirement - Example B (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 14. Effects of 1959 amendment of Trust Annuity Plan for pilots of Trans World Airlines (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 15. Cost of Trans World Airlines of pilots' opening proposal that minimum retirement benefit be increased to $700. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 16. Company cost involved in involuntary retirement at age 55. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 17. "TWA Cooperative Group Insurance Plan." (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 18. Growth in airline traffic, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 19. United States flag carriers' share of Transatlantic market, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 20. United States flag carriers' share of Transatlantic seating capacity, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 21. Trend in passenger mile yield domestic trunks and Trans-Atlantic United States flag carriers in current dollars and in 1950 dollars, 1951- 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 22. Trends in revenue per passenger mile, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 23. Coach/economy constitutes an increasing percent of total passenger traffic, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 24. Price stability index of domestic trunk airline fares and general prices, 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 25. Distribution of the operating revenue dollar. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 26. Trans World Airlines cockpit crew payroll cost percent of total payroll cost and cockpit crew percent of total employees, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    12 months ending September 30, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 27. Average annual salary of pilots and co-pilots "Big Four" systems., 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 28. The trend of Trans World Airline pilots annual average salary and wage. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Compared with consumer price index, Trans World Airline passenger revenue per passenger mile, and Trans World Airline operating revenue per revenue ton mile.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 29. "Wages of TWA jet captains compared with the salaries of high level executive, professional, administration, and technical positions in TWA, private industry and government." (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 30. Wages of Trans World Airline captains compared with salaries of comparable positions in other modes of transportation., 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 31. United States pilots really tip the pay scales. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 32. Air transport pay has increased faster in the United States than in other countries. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 33. Changes in wage rates negotiated during 1960 (manufacturing). (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 34. Domestic trunk line earnings statistics., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 35. Trans World Airlines system earnings statistics., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 36. Trans World Airlines net profit margin on revenue by division., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 37. International operations of domestic trunk lines and Pan American system earnings statistics., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 38. Operating profit margins (before and after depreciation) on comparable basis for selected regulated industries., 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 39. Excerpt from the report of the Task Force on National Aviation Goals "Project Horizon." "The Airline Financial Posture." (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 40. Trans World Airline's Financial Report for October 1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    October 1961
  - Carriers' Exhibit 41. Computation of Trans World Airline captain monthly pay (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 42. Captain, First Officer and Second Officer monthly earnings at 80 hours of flying under agreement signed May 22, 1959, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Also includes company proposal dated October 20, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 43. Captain, First Officer, and Second Officer monthly earnings at 85 hours of flying under agreement signed May 22, 1959., 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 44. Ninth year domestic captain monthly earnings at 80 hours of flying by equipment flown - Trans World, American, Eastern, and United Airlines. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 45. Ninth year domestic captain monthly earnings at 85 hours of flying by equipment flown - Trans World, American, Eastern, and United Airlines. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 46. International senior captain monthly earnings at 80 and 85 hours of flying by equipment flown, Trans World Airlines-Pan American Airlines. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 47. Additional cost to Trans World Airlines of Air Line Pilots Association pay proposal, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Proposal dated November 28, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 48. Comparison of monthly yields Trans World Air Lines - Air Line Pilots Association proposals, 80 hours flying, one half day - one half night. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 49. Pegged speed. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 50. Areas of agreement and dispute and position of the parties. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 51. Pilot rates for hotel-motel, domestic. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 52. Comparison of estimated expenses incurred per pilot suggested schedule versus trip expenses received. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 53. Trans World Airlines system passenger miles, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 54. Flight crew scheduling. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 55. Pilot payroll - non-productive pay and credits for each dollar of flight pay, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    September 1960- August 1961
  - Carriers' Exhibit 56. Utilization of captains, domestic operation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    July 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 57. Utilization of first officers, domestic operation., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 58. Utilization of second officers, domestic operation., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 59. Utilization of pilots, international operation., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 60. Trend of Trans World Airlines captains' pay hours and actual flight hours. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 61. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignment - total hours on duty (domestic) (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 62. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total hours at home (domestic). (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 63. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignment - total hours at home (domestic) (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 64. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total calendar days at home (domestic). (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 65. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total hours on duty (International). (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 66. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total hours away from home. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 67. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total hours at home (International). (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 68. Present agreement - jet captain flight assignments - total calendar days at home (International). (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 69. International division captains holding bids effective October 29, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 70. Normal flight pairing reflecting application of actual or schedule hours, whichever is greater, and determination of operational duty time. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 71. Normal flight pairing reflecting one hour credit for every two hours on duty with minimum of two hours and maximum six hours credit per duty period. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 72. Normal flight pairing reflecting one hour credit for every four trip hours. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 73. Normal flight pairing reflecting both one hour credit for every two hours on duty with two hour minimum, six hour maximum, and one hour credit for every four trip hours. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 74. Shows the normal flight assignments for the traffic schedules effective October 29, 1961 as they are flown under the existing agreement. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 75. Air Line Pilots Association proposal on working conditions. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 76. General comments upon Air Line Pilots Association's position with regard to hours of service. (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 77. President Kennedy opposed to workweek reduction. (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 78. Company proposal on working conditions. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 79. Addition to Exhibit 50, Section 11, hours of service. (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 80. Average length of hop "big four" airlines., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 81. Average segment miles by equipment., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 82. Reference Air Line Pilots Association Exhibit Number 103, page 2, line 1. (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 83. Reference Air Line Pilots Association Exhibit Number 103, page 2, line 2. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 84. Reference Air Line Pilots Association Exhibit Number 103, page 2, line 11. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 85. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 7, line 3 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 86. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 8, line 3. (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 87. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 9, line 11. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 88. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 10, line 1. (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 89. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 11, line 7. (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 90. Reference Air Line Pilots Association exhibit Number 103, page 4, line 6. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 91. Seniority of captains holding bids on Paris-Rome shuttle flights. (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 82. Trans World Airlines pilot payroll and travel expense analysis. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 93. Trans World Airline pilot pay hour analysis. (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 94. Second officer payroll and travel expense system., 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    September 1960-August 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 95. Payroll, company trust annuity contribution, and total earnings for the five most senior and the five least senior pilots by division based on bid status, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 96. Summary of costs resulting from air Line Pilots Association's original proposal based on fourth quarter 1960 schedules. (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 97. Summary of increased expense. Air Line Pilots Association, October 1961 proposal versus present contract based on October 29, 1961 schedules. (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 98. Comparison - Air Line Pilots Association proposal (November 30, 1961) versus present contract based on October 29, 1961 schedules. (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 99. Anticipated reduction in number of group A flight engineers as designated by the Presidential Commission on the airlines controversy (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 100. Summary of added costs resulting from application of recommendations by the Presidential Commission in the airlines controversy., 1962- 1975 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 101. Consumer price indexes in foreign countries by quarter., 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 102. Meal expense allowance comparison. (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 103. Excerpt from "Tipsfor travel abroad - what to know before you go." (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 104. Sample menus - London. (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 105. Sample menus - Paris. (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 106. Sample menus - Frankfurt area. (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 107. Sample menus - Rome. (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 108. Excerpt from Alson's Aboard and Abroad in Europe. (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 109. Increased productivity is the result of increased capital investment by the carrier. (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 110. Trans World Airlines aircraft introduction dates and acquisition cost. (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 111. No strike clauses. (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 112. Mr. C. N. Saying's letter addressed to the Air Line Pilots Association., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    October 31, 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 113. Excerpt from Air Line Pilots Association Policy Manual., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    May 1961.
  - Carriers' Exhibit 114. Excerpt from second interim report. Air Line Pilots Association wage and working conditions. Policy Committee February 8, 1960 - Compensation. (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 115. Excerpt from second interim report. Air Line Pilots Association wage and working conditions. Policy Committee, February 8 1960 - Summary regarding compensation. (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Carriers' Exhibit 116. Excerpt from second interim report. Air Line Pilots Association wage and working conditions policy committee, February 8, 1960 - Working Conditions. (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Union Exhibit 1. Letter from C.N. Sawyer, President of the air Line Pilots Association to D.J. Crombie, Vice President - Industrial Relations of Trans World Airlines (Box 1, Folder 118)
    Informing the Mr. Crombie that the Air Line Pilots Association would like to make changes in the agreement after it expires.
  - Union Exhibit 2. Proposed pilots' employment agreement. (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Union Exhibit 3. Trans World Airlines - Air Line Pilots Association agreement, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    Effective May 22, 1959-November 22, 1960.
  - Union Exhibit 4. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Union Exhibit 5. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Union Exhibit 6. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Union Exhibit 7. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Union Exhibit 8. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Union Exhibit 9. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Union Exhibit 10. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Union Exhibit 11. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Union Exhibit 12. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Union Exhibit 13. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Union Exhibit 14. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Union Exhibit 15. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Union Exhibit 16. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Union Exhibit 17. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Union Exhibit 18. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Union Exhibit 19. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Union Exhibit 20. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - Union Exhibit 21. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Union Exhibit 22. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Union Exhibit 23. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Union Exhibit 24. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Union Exhibit 25. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Union Exhibit 26. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Union Exhibit 27. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Union Exhibit 28. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Union Exhibit 29. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Union Exhibit 30. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Union Exhibit 31. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Union Exhibit 32. Letters and telegrams between parties and national mediation board. (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Union Exhibit 33. Types of equipment by airline. (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Union Exhibit 34. 707 specifications. (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - Union Exhibit 35. Trans World Airlines aircraft by types. (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Union Exhibit 36. Airline abbreviations. (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Union Exhibit 37. Comparative aircraft pegged speeds. (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - Union Exhibit 38. Captain's base or longevity pay by airline and years of service. (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Union Exhibit 39. Captain's hourly rates by airline and type of equipment. (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Union Exhibit 40. Captain's mileage rates by airline. (Box 1, Folder 157)